In this week, you'll hear
about sequence to
sequence models,
which are useful
for everything from
machine translation to
speech recognition.
Let's start with
the basic models,
and then later this week,
you'll hear about beam search,
the attention model, and we
will wrap up the discussion
of models for audio
data like speech.
Let's get started. Let's
say you want to input
a French sentence like Jane
visite I'Afrique Septembre,
and you want to translate
it to the English sentence,
Jane is visiting
Africa in September.
As usual, let's use x1 through x,
in this case 5 to represent
the words and the input sequence,
and we'll use y1 through y6 to
represent the words in
the output sequence.
How can you train a
neural network to input
the sequence x and
output the sequence y?
Well, here's something
you could do.
The ideas I'm about to
present are mainly from
these two papers due
to Ilya Sutskever, Vinyals Oriol,
and V. Le. Quoc  and
that one by
Kyunghyun Cho, Bart van Merriënboer,
Caglar Gulcehre, Dzmitry Bahdanau,
Fethi Bougares, Holger Schwenk, and Yoshua Bengio.
First, let's have a network
which we're going to call
the encoder network be built as
a RNN and this could be a
Gru or LSTM feeding
the input French words
one word at a time.
After ingesting the
input sequence the RNN
then outputs a vector that
represents the input sentence.
After that, you can
build a decoded network,
which you might draw here.
Which takes as input
the encoding output by
the encoding network shown
in black on the left,
and then can be trained to output
the translation one
word at a time.
Eventually, it helps
us say the end of
sequence and the sentence token
upon which the decoder
stops, and as usual,
we could take the
generator tokens
and feed them to the next
so if they just stay in the
sequence they were doing
before when synthesizing text
using the language model.
One of the most
remarkable recent results
in deep learning is
that this model works.
Given enough pairs of French
and English sentences,
if you train a model to input
a French sentence and
output the corresponding
English translation,
this will actually
work decently well.
This model simply uses an
encoding network whose job it
is to find an encoding of
the input French sentence,
and then use a decoding
network to then
generate the corresponding
English translation.
An architecture very similar to
this also works for
image captioning.
Given an image like
the one shown here,
maybe you wanted to be captions
automatically as a cat
sitting on a chair.
How do you train
in your network to
input an image and output
a caption like that
phrase up there?
Here's what you can do.
From the earlier course
on the ConvNets,
you've seen and how you can input
an image into a
convolutional network,
may maybe a pre-trained AlexNet,
and have that learn and encoding
a learner to the features
of the input image.
This is actually the
AlexNet architecture,
and if we get rid of
this final softmax unit,
the pre-trained AlexNet
can give you a
4,096-dimensional
feature vector of
which to represent
this picture of a cat.
This pre-trained network can
be the encoded network
for the image and you
now have a 4,096-dimensional
vector that represents the image.
You can then take
this and feed it to
an RNN whose job it is to
generate the caption
one word at a time.
Similar to what we saw
with machine translation,
translating from
French the English,
you can now input
a feature vector describing
the inputs and then
have it generate an
output set of words,
one word at a time.
This actually works pretty
well for image captioning,
especially if the
caption you want to
generate is not too long.
As far as I know, this type
of model was first proposed by
Jin Hwan Mau Wei Xu Yong Chung Wang, Xiao Hong and Alan Yo. although it turns
out there are multiple
groups coming up with
very similar models independently
and at about the same time.
Two of the groups that had done
very similar work at
about the same time and
I think independently of
Junhua Mao, Wei Xu, Yi Yang, Jiang Wang, Zhiheng Huang,
Alan L. Yuille as well as Adrej
Karpathy and Fei-Fei Li.
You've now seen how
a basic sequence to
sequence model works.
How basic image to sequence,
or image captioning model works.
But there are some
differences between
how you'll run a model like this,
the generally the sequence
compared to how you were
synthesizing novel text
using a language model.
One of the key differences
is you don't want
to randomly choose
in translation.
You may be want the
most likely translation
or you don't want to
randomly choose in caption,
maybe not, but you might want
the best caption and
most likely caption.
Let's see in the next video how
you go about generating that.